Michael Heffner

 Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, United States
 ■ michaelheffnercruz@gmail.com
 □ (267) 648-2137

https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-heffner-492013193/

SUMMARY

Adaptable recent college graduate with a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, with a focus on Artificial Intelligence and Video Game Development and Production, with 1.5+ years of work experience. Designer and programmer of a multiple award winning game, Sons of Ra.

EXPERIENCE

Research Engineer

Drexel University

March 2016 - September 2016, Philadelphia, PA

- · Developed a visualization tool in Java to compare and analyze data points of various types.
- · Wrote documentation on the project at graduate levels of detail and information.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Worked in close relation with the teams and people that would be using the tool.

Designer and Programmer

Pharaoh Hound Games

June 2018 - current, Philadelphia, PA

- Designed and balanced gameplay for a multiplayer tower defense game.
- Programmed systems that would be used in the minute to minute gameplay.
- · Work in every aspect of the game, from initial conception of an idea to full implementation.

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence and Game Development Concentration.

Drexel University · Philadelphia, PA · 2019

COURSEWORK

Games Studio Workshop

Computer Science · Programming

Designed and programmed a video game from inception to a minimum viable product across six months.

Artificial Intelligence

Computer Science · problem solving and information gathering.

Programmed and trained various types of AI across multiple languages.

Serious Game Design

Game Art and Production · Research and teamwork

researched about serious game design and applied that knowledge making two different games with a group of three.

INVOLVEMENT

Entrepreneurial Game Studios

Drexel University, Philadelphia. • Member of incubator project. • June 2018 - June 2019

- Participated in group exercises to talk about current and upcoming design about recently released games with guest invites from the industry.
- · Actively worked in my own incubator project with my team with assistance of mentors that have been in the industry.
- Provided assistance and critiques to other projects in the organization.

SKILLS

Development Languages: .NET, C#, C++, Java, SQL, Python, Unity, Unreal

Languages: English, Spanish, German